Contact

+917902983757 (Home) nader684@yahoo.co.in

www.linkedin.com/in/nadersalam-92479795 (LinkedIn) npayeaws.s3.apsouth-1.amazonaws.com/ index.html (Portfolio)

Top Skills

.NET

Microsoft SQL Server MySQL

Publications

Masked RCNN+ fast boosted tree classifier: a combination of deep learning technology for neural networks and classifier for pedestrian detection

Nader Salam

Full Stack Developer

Ernakulam

Summary

I'm a IT MANAGER, with an experience of 13+ years and has been dividing my time between Mobile App Development, Web Development with Php and Django and front end development using React. 5 years in Abu Dhabi, U.A.E as Senior IT Engineer. Currently I am working as IT MANAGER with NOWPREPAY MOZAMBIQUE S.A, Maputo Mozambique. I pride myself on never delivering anything less than perfection to our clients.

Experience

NOWPREPAY MOZAMBIQUE S.A, Maputo Mozambique IT Manager

January 2015 - April 2021 (6 years 4 months)

Designed and Developed the Customized in-house ERP for Now Prepay Mozambique.

Designed and Developed the Android App NpayE - Epayment App.

Designed and Developed Epayment web portal.

Integration with banks (BCI & MBIM) for automating Ewallet topup for merchants

API Integration with Service Providers to buy Credelec Token for Electricity

API Integration with Telecom Providers to buy Pins

Configure Active Directory Domain Controller using UBUNTU 14.04 with SAMBA.

#Configure Mail Server using POSTFIX, DOVECOT and MySQL.

Configures Muli Wan Router using UBUNTU.

Configured Network Firewall using IP TABLES

Configured File Servers.

Designed and Developed Intranet Application-Customer Support and Inventory Management.

ORACLE database Administrator for Rokel And Mobinet Banks -Sierra Leone.

Serve as project manager for deployment of new technologies with Partners like VODACOM, MOVITEL, MCEL, CREDLEC (Electricity Department of Mozambique).

Designing Crystal Reports for the various Departments using Oracle DB

Research and implement new innovative technologies that are capable of enhancing business productivity or reducing expenses.

Mint Electronic Payment Services
Sr IT Engineer
May 2010 - December 2014 (4 years 8 months)
Abu Dhabi UAE

Designing and developing E-Payment Web Application project using J2EE standard with JSF. Primefaces and JPA.

Design and develop reports for various departments using Java HTTPRequest and JPA.

Design and implemented network solution with UBUNTU 12.0.4 server and Netgear Switch including Firewall using IPTABLES ,DHCP Server, IP aliasing and creating VLANs.

Designed Nagios scripts to Monitor App Server, DB Server and Web Server running on Linux OS.

Proficient in Linux based Scripting like AWK Commandss.

Designed and developed automated File Handling app using Java Net beans and Ubuntu Linux Server 12.04..

Designed Portlets using Liferay portals Using Eclipse Juno.

Designed and Developed automated reporting software using PHP and MySql.

Managed company messaging system including Exchange 2003 with local disk and network attached storage, MAPI, IMAP,SMTP, and Trend Micro antispam/virus services.

Systems monitoring and administration of Servers for day-to-day problems, patches, User Administration, hardware failure, monitoring log files, backup, software up gradation, Configuration changes and documentation.

Analyzed corporate LAN and WAN to determine what were the major problems and improvements needed to be made to the network infrastructure

Maintained the infrastructure and application access security through implementing rigorous security features

Setting up crontab in Redhat ES4 for monitoring various applications from point to point

Key member in Implementing Debysis Application fro E-payment Solutions and migrating from Qcomm Application for E-PAY.

Migration from Microsoft Exchange to Google Apps, which was a more cost effective solution.

Aided for the implementation of KIOSK machines for Global Business Services

Turner and Miller Software Engineer March 2008 - April 2009 (1 year 2 months)

Education

University of Kerala

Master of Technology - MTech, Computer Science and Engineering · (July 2017 - July 2019)

University of Kerala

Engineer's Degree, Computer Science Engineering · (2002 - 2006)